RG 004:079, Marlborough Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Marlborough Probate Court records
1846-1945
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Marlborough)
4.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1846-1945; Files, 1846-1938.
RG004_079
1911-006 and 2011-115
Historical Note
Marlborough, Hartford County, Town established in October 1803, Parent Towns: Colchester, Hebron, and Glastonbury
The Marlborough Probate District was constituted June 11, 1846, from the Colchester Probate District. The Marlborough Probate District merged with the East Haddam, East Hampton, and Portland Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #14 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Haddam, East Hampton, Marlborough and Portland.
Town of Marlborough, Probate District chronology:
October 1803 - May 1832, East Haddam District (these records are included with those of the Colchester Probate District
May 1832 - June 10, 1846, Colchester District
June 11, 1846 - January 4, 2011, Marlborough District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #14 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1846-1945. Volume 5 was not transferred to the State Library. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 7. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1846-1938. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1846-1938 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered 1-4, 6-7. Volume 5 was not transferred to the State Library.
Probate files in accession 1911-006 are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1911-006 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Marlborough
Places:
Marlborough (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1938 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15.
Accession 2011-115, Record books, 1846-1945, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1, 2, 4, and 6, 1846-1937; probate files, 1846-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 30, 2011.
The probate files in accession 1911-006 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): November 9, 1911 (1846-1910); November 25, 1935 (1929-1934); July 12, 1939 (1911-1938). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
Container List
- Record books, 1846-1945; 3 cubic feet (6 volumes); 2011-115
  - Records, 1846-1862 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1863-1890 (Volume 2)
  - Orders and decrees, 1885-1995 (Volume 3)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1891-1913 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1913-1937 (Volume 6)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Records, 1933-1945 (Volume 7)
- Probate files, 1846-1938; 1.25 cubic feet; 1911-006
  - Aikley - Skinner (Drawer 1)
  - Smith - Zeugini; Miscellaneous (Drawer 2)
- Inventory Control Book, 1846-1938; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1911-006
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest